careerprofessor.works 2015-12-29

# Privacy Policy | CareerProfessor.works

     **Who is CareerProfessor?**

CareerProfessor.works (CareerProfessor) is part of Expertise in Labour Mobility BV (ELM). At CareerProfessor we are committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy sets out our privacy practices in relation to our business activities. Please take the time to review this document carefully as it tells you how your personal information will be treated by us. By using the CareerProfessor website or app, by taking part in any of our business activities or completing a survey launched by us, you consent to the collection, use and transfer of your personal information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.  
CareerProfessor supports students and alumni across the globe in their career path. We work with Higher Education Institutions (HEIs) all over the world in building and supporting alumni networks. We collect personal opinions and private information as this is central to our work and as a result, we take our responsibilities very seriously doing our utmost to protect the data we collect and the privacy of our respondents.

CareerProfessor will remain the sole owner of the information collected. Aggregated data may be shared with participating HEIs, however your name and email address will always be removed. We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries and any company under common ownership.

By participation in CareerProfessor you hereby agree to what is stated in this privacy policy.  
  
What this policy covers: • What data does CareerProfessor collect • Why does CareerProfessor collect this data • How does CareerProfessor collect data • What does CareerProfessor do with your data • How does CareerProfessor secure your data • Updating this privacy policy • Access to your information • Responsibility for external sites • Who to contact at CareerProfessor if you have a question

     **What data does CareerProfessor collect?**

CareerProfessor collects information that is both personally identifiable and unidentifiable about you through our app and website. Respondents must be over 16 years of age and a student or alumnus of an HEIs.  
Participation in CareerProfessor is entirely voluntary.  
The data we collect during the registration process (name, year of graduation, email address) is meant to identify you as a student or alumnus of a participating HEI and to activate your login.  
The data we collect in CareerProfessor is career related information.

     **Why does CareerProfessor collect this data?**

The data we collect in CareerProfessor is reported back in aggregated format to the HEI from which you graduated to help the HEI improve their careers advice to its students and alumni and enhance the connection to their alumni.  
CareerProfessor will not disclose, without your consent, personal information collected about you, except for certain explicit circumstances in which disclosure is required by law. CareerProfessor will not distribute or sell personal information to external parties other than your own HEI. 

Results of CareerProfessor research may be released into the public domain, but this will always be in an aggregated format and no personal information will be disclosed, unless specific prior consent is received. 

     **How does CareerProfessor collect data?**

CareerProfessor collects data via webforms, surveys and the registration process.

CareerProfessor uses browser-IP-address information and anonymous-browser history to report information about site accesses and for profiling purposes. This information is used to improve web presentation and utilisation. IP address information may also be used for troubleshooting purposes.  
  
CareerProfessor makes use of geolocation data to be able to provide users with information on their peers.  You will be provided with a notice asking your permission before we ask for geolocation data.  
CareerProfessor may make use of “cookies” to gather additional information relating to internet usage. You are able to decline the cookies by changing the “accept cookies” setting on your web browser but please be aware that this will affect the functionality of CareerProfessor.  

     **What does CareerProfessor do with your data?**

CareerProfessor will use aggregated data to provide reports to the HEI from which you graduated. 

Contact details will not be given to any external parties for marketing purposes and you will not receive any communications from external parties as a result of taking part in CareerProfessor. 

     **How does CareerProfessor secure your data?**

CareerProfessor is committed to storing data securely and takes security measure to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of stored information. Use of the data collected is restricted to use for business requirements including (but not exclusively) research analysis, data processing and addressing of queries, technical problems, ensuring that content from CareerProfessor is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your device.  
Please make sure your login details and passwords are treated with care. You are fully responsible for maintaining the confidentiality and ensuring the security of your account.   
Sensitive personal information is encrypted during any transmission.

     **Updating this privacy policy**

In order to ensure your privacy, we reserve the right to change this policy at any time and for any reason. Any changes we make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on our website and, where appropriate, notified to you by email. With this in mind, you are encouraged to review this policy frequently. This policy was created on 15 July 2014.  

     **Access to your information**

Should you wish this, we like to reassure you that you have a right of access to the personal data we store. Any access request may be subject to a fee of 25 Euro to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

     **Responsibility for external sites**

CareerProfessor may, occasionally, contain links to and from other websites which are outside our control. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

     **Who to contact at CareerProfessor if you have a question?**

Questions regarding this policy and its implementation should be directed to: data.guardian@careerprofessor.works
